DHR&Hakugetsu Sub
翻譯：因果律 モビイ·ディック 大湿 時間軸：水姬 後期：水姬 壓制：沙夏 KoU
おはよう
ごきげんよう
ウフフ…
It's not as though I didn't
have fun, by any means.
決して
楽しくないわけではないのです
- There, didn't I tell you so?
- However, I thought
that everyone kept the pain
- There, didn't I tell you so?
けれど　誰もが笑顔の下に
that they couldn't tell to anyone
else hidden behind a smiling face.
人に言えないつらさを
隠してると思ってました
Isn't that a surprise?
驚きません？
とてもビックリですわ
I am quite astonished.
Nemurenai yoru ni kiita monogatari ga
What if the story I heard that sleepless night
esoragoto da to shitara
was all just an impossible dream?
Eien wo shiru yori kairaku wo motomete
What if I pursue pleasure, and lament the moment
ima wo kuyande shimau no wa
instead of learning about the eternities
kokoro no fukaku ni sumitsuita kage kara
so that I can escape from the shadows
nigeru tame da to shitara
that dwell deep within my heart?
Sore demo atashi wa atashi wa ai shite irareru nara
But even so, as long as I, as long as I can still keep loving
Hanbun ni wareta taiyou ga asa wo tsurete kite
The sun split in half brings with it the morning
yami ni nareta shinkei wo jiwari shigeki suru
gradually stimulating my nerves, so used to the darkness
Okiwasureta ano ai wa aete sono mama de
I'll dare to leave the love that I'd misplaced as it is
Shinario no kieta monogatari wa
A story whose plot has been erased,
jiyuu ni jiyuu ni kaji wo totte
freely, freely, takes the helm,
motto takaku e maiagatte
soaring ever higher
No!!
ＮＯ！
"It Was... Successful"
You can relax your legs.
足　崩したら？
Oh, right. Thank you very much.
あ…　はい
ありがとうございます
Um, her friends are ripping
open her stomach and eating her.
あの…
これ　お仲間の方が
おなかを裂かれて
食べられてますよ
だって　ゾンビは人間を襲って
食べるもんだから
Well, attacking people and
eating them is what zombies do.
食べる？
Eat them?
This is surprising. She said
she's never seen a zombie movie,
意外だな　ゾンビ映画
見たことないって言ってたから
so I brought a pretty gruesome one,
きっついやつ持ってきたのに
すげえマジメに見てるよ
- yet she's watching it so intently...
すごい…　いっぱい出てる
- Wow... So much... blood...
- yet she's watching it so intently...
She must have some
fortitude, being a rich girl.
お嬢だから　根が固いんだな
つ～か　そろそろ
手伝ってほしいんすけど
So anyway, I could use
your help here about now.
Oh, I'm sorry. I got caught up in it.
あッ　ごめんなさい
つい見入っちゃって
Would you pluck these?
これ　むしって
はい
Yes.
So, what kind of poisonous
plant are you planning to try today?
で　今日は　どんな毒草を
試してみるつもりですか？
Hmm, I got nothing.
う～ん…　ネタ切れ
え～ッ！
Even if we make this as it says,
このとおりに作ったとしても
死んだ者が
it's doubtful whether or not
anything dead will come back to life,
蘇ったりするかどうかは
ビミョーだし
and we can't even read part of it to begin with.
そもそも　一部分　読めねえし
Th-Then, what's going to happen to Babu?
じゃあ　ばーぶちゃんは
どうするんですか？
Hmm, why don't we bury him, already?
うん…　もう埋めてあげようか
え～ッ！
I mean, it's been five days.
だって　５日目だぜ
Unless you'd rather eat him...?
もしくは　お前が食っちまうか
いや～ッ！
何てことを思いつくんです
No! H-How could you even think of such a thing?
I-I couldn't do that to Babu.
ば…　ばーぶちゃんを　そんな
She really can't tell a
joke when she hears one.
ホント　冗談　通じねえんだな
For that matter, I've used
just about every poisonous plant
とは言っても
もう　身近で手に入る毒草は
that I can get my hands on around here.
大体　使ってみたからな
アサガオにスズランだろ
There are morning glories
and lilies of the valley, right?
Then water hemlock,
Chinese plums, and what else?
ドクゼリにウメに
あと　何だろ…　え～と
Let's see...
あッ　ちょっと待ってください
Just a moment, please.
I'll go get some!
今から採ってきます
えッ？
お～い　何を採りに…
Hey, what are you getting?
She's surprisingly forward, huh?
意外と攻め系なんだな
My father's affections
toward me had been aberrant.
父の私に対する愛情は
常軌を逸していました
Mistress Rea, the bunny says
she wants to play with you now!
礼弥お嬢様　今度は
うさぎさんが
遊びたいそうですよ
Over here, Mistress. Come on...
お嬢様こちらですよ　さあ
Oh dear, Mistress...
まあ　お嬢様
It's all right. Don't cry, now.
Come along, Mistress, you're strong.
大丈夫ですよ　泣かないで
ほら　お嬢様　強いですね
At some point or other,
that maid was dismissed.
そのメイドは
いつの間にか暇を出されました
ニャーン
That cat never showed itself again,
and the maids also went away.
そのネコはニ度と姿を現さず
メイド達もいなくなりました
But what always remained until the end
そして　いつも　最後に残るのは
私に冷たい母の亞里亞だけ
was my mother, Aria,
who gave me the cold shoulder.
Rea, I'll take another
picture of you this year.
礼弥　今年も
写真を撮ってあげようね
Now, open your eyes and smile.
さあ　目を開けて笑いなさい
It was about this time
この頃になると
これが普通のことではないと
that I began realizing
that this wasn't normal.
分かってきていました
My mother appeared to be aware
of my father's feelings toward me.
母は私に対する父の気持ちを
悟っているようでした
I couldn't bear the situation.
私は　いたたまれませんでした
I always felt the presence of my father,
私は常に父とその配下の者達の
気配を感じていました
and those who served under him.
Their gaze always followed me,
wherever I went, clinging to me.
いつ　どこにいても
まとわりつくような視線
Rea!
礼弥～　おっはよう
Good morning!
What's the matter? You seem down.
どうしたの？　元気ないね
ううん　何でもないよ
Mm-mm, it's nothing.
Good morning.
おはよう
彼女は　私にできた
初めての友達らしい友達でした
She's the first friend I ever
had that seemed like a friend.
"Nakadai"
I came to know her because
she was from a privileged family, too,
彼女との付き合いは
良家の子女ということもあって
and my father gave his approval.
父も黙認してくれました
I thought that everyone kept the pain
私は誰もが笑顔の下に
人に言えない  つらさを
抱えているものだと思っていた
that they couldn't tell to anyone
else hidden behind a smiling face.
But through my association with her,
でも　彼女との付き合いで
I learned that that wasn't the case.
それは違うのだと知りました
I was just unhappy.
私が不幸なだけだったのです
Do you really mean that?
それ　本当？
Mm-hmm. This is the first time I've told anyone.
初めて話した　こんなこと
What he's doing isn't right! I mean,
おかしいよ！　そんなの
だって…
his own daughter, naked...
娘の裸なんて…
I know...
だよね
You should speak up.
Tell him to please stop.
言った方がいいよ
「やめてください」って
Mm-hmm... But...
うん…　でも
My dad and I argue
about things all the time.
私なんて　お父さんと年中
ケンカばっかしだよ
You have to tell him to stop,
even if it causes a big fight.
大ゲンカしてでも
やめさせないとダメ！
Would it really be
okay to start a fight with him?
ケンカなんかして…　平気かな？
It'll be fine.
You're his daughter, after all.
平気だよ　親子だもん
I came to bitterly regret having
confessed this to her that night.
このとき　彼女に告白したことを
私は　ひどく
後悔することになったのです
She's taking too long.
遅い…
ひょっとして山で迷ってるとか？
I wonder if she got lost
in the mountains or something.
Or maybe she slipped down
the rocks and fell into the river.
あるいは
岩場から滑り落ちて川に…
Nah, she wouldn't
do anything that dangerous.
まあ　そんな
危なっかしいことはしないか
オイッ！
どこ　よじ登ってんだよ  アイツは！
Hey!
Where does she think she's climbing up?!
Furuya...
降谷君…
Geez, Princess, you need a nanny.
まったく
お嬢にはお守り役が必要だな
H-How rude! I can climb
up this slope all by myself!
し…　失礼ね
こんな斜面
１人で登れます！
Well, want me to let go?
じゃあ　離そうか
No, hold on a minute!
ちょっと待って！
So, why would you do something like that?
で　何で　また　あんなことを？
W-Well... when I went looking,
だ…　だって
探してたら
下のお墓あたりで  咲いているのが見えて
I saw that they were blooming
down near that graveyard,
and thought that it was closer to
climb straight down and up again.
直接　登り下りした方が
近いかなって
For a princess, you sure are a daredevil.
お嬢のくせに　命知らずだな
I'm fine.
平気です
だって　私が死んでも
After all, even if I died, Furuya,
降谷君が
ゾンビとして  生き返らせてくれるし
you'd bring me back to life as a zombie.
Hey, you! Not even Babu's
reanimation has been successful.
オイオイ！　まだ
ばーぶの蘇生自体
成功してねえし
And even if it was, did I ever
say I would bring you back to life?
成功したとしても
俺がお前を 生き返らせるなんて
言ったか？
Well, I'll say it now.
じゃあ　今　言っておきます
I want you to bring
me back to life. If you please.
生き返らせてください
お願いします
何だって？
What did you say?
No. Would you please stop doing this?
イヤです
もう　やめてくれませんか
こういうことは
Why?
どうしてだ？
As a parent, it's only natural for me to leave
親として
娘の成長記録を残すことは
当然のことだよ
a record of his daughter's growth.
This isn't natural!
こんなの　当然じゃありません！
Can't we be like normal fathers and daughters?
普通の親子のように
なれませんか？
I want us to be normal, Father.
私は普通がいいんです　お父様
Did someone say something to you?
誰かに何かを言われたか？
No...
いいえ
They did, didn't they?
言われたのだな？
I think anyone would find
this strange to hear about!
こんなの誰が聞いても
おかしいと思います！
Rea, you don't understand.
You just don't understand.
礼弥　お前は分かっていない
分かっていないのだ
There is only one thing
in this world that is right,
この世で正しいのは　ただ１つ
and that thing is my affection toward you.
お前に対する
私の愛情だけだということを
I had an uneasy feeling.
イヤな予感がしました
Transferred?
転校！？
Something suddenly came up with her father.
何か急にお父様のご都合で
I heard he had to
resign from his company.
会社を辞めなきゃ
ならなくなったんですって
It happened again. He had
taken something else from me...
まただ　また　あの人は私から…
Thank goodness! I thought
I might never see you again.
よかった　もう
会えないかもしれないと思って
The place we're moving
to won't let us keep pets,
次に越す所
ペット飼えないんだって
so I'm going to the
public health center now.
だから　今から保健所に行くの
この子ともお別れ
I have to say goodbye to her.
My mom and dad are acting really funny.
お父さんもお母さんも
おかしくなってる
All over something I didn't do...
身に覚えのないことで
こんな…
One of my relatives told me what happened!
親戚が教えてくれたよ！
What did you say to your father?!
That I did something bad to you?!
あなた　お父さんに
何言ったの！？
私　あなたに
何か悪いことした！？
N-No, I wouldn't...
そんな　私…
I should have never been your friend.
あなたなんかと
仲よくするんじゃなかった
He takes everything I have from me.
あの人は私から
何もかも奪ってしまう
You still do not understand.
お前は
まだ分かっていないのだ
幸せの形は　人それぞれ違う
Happiness takes different forms
for different people.
The pureness of the
affection I have toward you
私のお前に対する愛情の
純粋さは
is something that other
people cannot comprehend.
余人には理解できないものだ
I don't want to understand it.
そんなの
理解したくもありません
Someday, you will understand
the depths of my love.
いつかは分かる　私の愛の深さが
The only love of its kind in
the world, unlike anything else.
何にも似ていない
この世でただ１つの愛の形が
Rea, if you don't come to understand it,
礼弥　お前が
それを理解しないと
it's just going to make someone else unhappy.
また　誰かが
不幸になるだけだぞ
You are my extraordinary girl.
贅沢な娘だ
How can you not realize that
you live in a far happier environment
誰よりも幸福な環境に
いるというのに
それに　気づいていないなんて
than everyone else around you?
Rea, take off your clothes.
礼弥　脱ぎなさい
If me trying to be happy is going
to make someone else unhappy...
私が幸せになろうとして
誰かが不幸になるのなら…
Happy birthday, Rea.
ハッピーバースデー　礼弥
きっと　不幸のままでいた方が
いいのでしょう
...then I'm sure it would be
better for me to remain unhappy.
Okay, let's hurry up and
use what I went and picked!
さあ　早速　採ってきた
アレを使ってみましょう
つっても　それって…
Yeah, but isn't that...
Yes, a hydrangea.
はい　アジサイです
Hey, are you telling me that
the hydrangeas that normally bloom
町なかで普通に咲いてる
アジサイに毒があるってか？
all over town are poisonous?
Yes. It may not be all that well-known,
ええ　そんなに
知られていないかもしれないけど
but my family crest bears the hydrangea,
私の家って　家紋がアジサイで
and we have lots of
them growing on our premises.
敷地にも
いっぱい植えられてるんです
So ever since I was little,
それで　小さい頃から
よく口に含まないよう
my father always warned
me not to put them in my mouth.
お父様から
注意を受けていましたので
Huh? But...
でもさ…
ウチの　爺ちゃんとかボケてて
...my grandpa sometimes nibbles
hydrangea leaves absentmindedly.
ときどき　アジサイの葉っぱ　かじってるけど
Huh? M-Maybe it's different for some people.
ええッ！？　人によるんですかね
Hydrangea leaves really are poisonous!
Please do not do this!!
A-Anyhow, let's try using this today.
と…　とにかく
今日は
これを使ってみましょうよ
Okay then, let's give it a try.
それじゃ　やってみるか
It's done.
できた
ちょっと　これ持ってて
ばーぶ出すから
Hold this for a second. I'll get Babu out.
Babu, come back to life.
ばーぶ…　蘇ってくれよ
Let me have the mixture.
薬　貸して
Here.
はい
Babu, today's the day.
ばーぶちゃん　今日こそ
That's too bad, huh?
B-But I'm sure it will be all right.
残念でしたね
でも　きっと大丈夫ですよ
Let's try another poisonous
plant as the ingredient tomorrow.
また　明日
別の毒草を材料にしてみましょう
No...
いや…
Let's give it up.
もう　やめよう
Keep Out
I'd feel too bad,
forcing my selfish wishes on Babu...
さすがに　これ以上は
ばーぶがかわいそうだよ
...any longer than I already have.
俺のワガママに
付き合わせるのは
Sorry about this, Babu.
I'll bury you now.
悪かったな　ばーぶ
もう埋めてやるからさ
Yes... you're right.
そう…　ですね
It's already too late today.
今日は　もう遅いしさ
明日また　２人で埋めてやろうぜ
Let's get together
again tomorrow and bury him.
Thanks for all the
assistance you've given me.
今まで　手伝ってくれて
ありがとうな
You've been a big help.
助かったぜ
Okay... Well, I guess I won't ever
see you here again, huh, Furuya?
そっか…　じゃあ　もう
ここで  降谷君と会うことも　なくなるんですね
N-Nothing. Let's head home.
さあ　帰りましょうか
Well then, I'll see you tomorrow.
それじゃ　また明日
Hey, you...
オイ　お前…
You're limping a little, aren't you?
ちょっと　足　引きずってねえか？
O-Oh, I twisted my foot
a little when I fell earlier.
さっき　足を滑らせたときに
ひねって
But I'm fine. I can make it home.
でも　大丈夫ですよ
家までは
Sheesh...
まったく…
ああッ！　ちょっと何するんですか
J-Just a minute! What are you doing?!
ヤ～ダ　どこ触って…
Oh, no! Watch your hands!
Why was I born into that family?
なぜ　私は　あの家に
生まれてしまったのでしょう
どうして　みんなのような
普通の家庭に 生まれなかったのか
Why wasn't I born into a regular
household, like everyone else?
I want to live an ordinary life.
当たり前に生きたい
I want to smile from
the heart, like everyone else.
みんなのように　心から笑いたい
Welcome home, Mistress.
お帰りなさいませ　お嬢様
ただいま
I'm home.
That's why I want to be reborn.
だから　生まれ変わりたい
生まれ変わって　自由になりたい
I want to be reborn, and be free.
And if I can't do that, then I'd rather be...
それができないなら…　いっそ
This is okay?
ここで　いいのか？
Yes.
はい
Your house is the estate up that hill, right?
お前んち　あの坂の上の屋敷だろ
I could take you up higher.
もう少し上がってっても…
No, that's all right.
Me being out is a secret,
いえ　結構です
内緒で外出してるから
so instead of using the front,
正面からじゃなくて
I always come and go through
this secret path between the bushes.
いつも　そこの草むらの奥にある
抜け道から出入りしてるの
あッ　な～る
Oh, that makes sense.
I can still do so, since my
father hasn't caught on yet.
まだ　お父様に
感づかれてないからいいものの
I really am a daredevil, huh?
私って　本当に命知らずですよね
オイオイ
どんだけ　親父　怖～んだよ
Hey, man, just how scared
of her old man is she?
あッ　じゃあ
ばーぶちゃん　返しますね
Oh, here, I'll give you Babu back.
Yeah.
おう
See you.
じゃあな
Mm-hmm.
Don't be late for Babu's funeral tomorrow!
明日のばーぶの葬儀　遅れんなよ
Yeah, of course not!
ええ　もちろん！
Bye.
じゃあ
What in the world...?
何という…
Rea!
礼弥！
"Babu"
Welcome home.
おっかえり～
W-Wanko! What are you doing at our house?
わんこ！
何でウチにいるんだよ
I came to return your DVD.
ＤＶＤ　返しにきたの
Don't go using our bath without asking.
人んちの風呂
勝手に入んなっての
Who cares? I'm your cousin.
いいじゃん　イトコなんだし
Now then...
さ～て
...why don't you tell me where
you've been, out until this late?
こ～んな遅くに　どこ行ってたか
吐いてもらいましょうかね
Damn it! She caught me off-guard!
チクショー　不意打ちだった
Today, I got some ice cream
at the convenience store,
今日は　たまたま　コンビニでアイス買って
河原で寝そべってて
and have been lying down, down by the river.
Huh? That's odd.
あ～れ　おっかしいな～
From what your sister was saying,
妹さんが言うには
ばーぶちゃんが亡くなった日から
毎晩　どこかに出かけてるって　聞いたんだけど
I'd heard that you've been going somewhere
every night since Babu died.
And with that cooler in hand, too.
しかも　あ～んな箱　持ってさ～
O-Oh, that...? I wanted
to have a river raft adventure...
あれは…
川下りアドベンチャーがしたくて
Come on, what's inside here?
ちょっと　これ何入れてんのよ？
コラッ！ひょっとして
Hey! That's...
Don't tell me your zombie
interest got the best of you,
アンタのゾンビ趣味が高じて
and you've gone and done
something awful to Babu's body!
ばーぶちゃんの亡きがらに
ひどいことを
No! Wait!
待て！
Huh? Wha...?
That couldn't have been...
えッ…　今のって　まさか
I-It was successful...
せ…　成功してた
I'm sorry, Furuya... Babu...
I can't make it tomorrow.
ごめん…　降谷君　ばーぶちゃん
明日　行けない
もう　二度と家から出さないって
He said he would never
let me out of the house again.
He won't even let me go to school.
学校にも行かせないって
And knowing Father, I'm sure he means it.
お父様なら　きっと本気だわ
I'm sorry. I actually
took a little bit of the mixture.
ごめんね…
あのお薬　実は少し　いただいちゃってたの
It didn't work to bring the dead back to life,
生き返らせる効果は　なかったけど
but it does have some poison in it.
これって
毒草なんかも入ってるんだし
逆の効果くらいは…
It will at least have the opposite effect...
I decided I would rather be dead.
私は　いっそ
死んでしまおうと思ったのです
Hitotsu dake kanau no nara
If I had just one wish
kimi no te no naka yureru chiisa na hana de itai
I would want to be a small flower, trembling in your hands
Hajimete miru mabushii kono sekai ga
Even if I become separated from you,
kimi to moshi hagureta to shite mo kitto
in this bright world I'm seeing for the first time,
mitsukedashite
I'm sure I'll find you
Mezametara soba ni iru yo
When I wake up, I'll stay beside you
ashita mo
tomorrow as well
Preview
なあ　いいかげんに　やめぬか
Hey, would you knock it off, already?
あまり　効果的とも思われぬが
I don't think it's very effective.
Huh? It's well received? That can't be right.
えッ…　好評？
そんなはずなかろう
Next time on Sankarea,
episode 3: "Sanka... Rea"
"Sanka... Rea"
Everybody watch mero!
みんな　見るメロ！
Would you let me see whoever wrote this?
とりあえず　これを書いた人間に
会わせてくれぬか
色々　言いたいことがあるのでな
I'd like to give them a piece of my mind.